[Toshiro Hijikata has become a hopeless otaku
because of the curse from a demonic sword.]
[What is Kamotaro Ito's ambition?! And
what is Sogo Okita's true intent?]
The NEET problem, the
hikikomori problem...
[NOTE: "NEET" is an acronym that stands for "Not currently engaged in employment, education, or training." In Japan, it refers to unmarried 15 to 30 year-olds who are unemployed, not in school, not training for a job, and not seeking work. A growing problem in Japan.]
(司会)ﾆｰﾄ問題 引きこもり問題｡
The number of apathetic young
people is steadily on the rise.
確実に
増え続ける無気力な若者たち｡
(司会)その予備軍といわれる
ｵﾀｸと呼ばれる存在｡
The people known as "Otaku" are said to
be NEETs and hikikomori in the making.
今日集まってもらったのは
ｵﾀｸを自称する100人｡
Today we have gathered one hundred
self-proclaimed otaku.
果たして彼らは 何を思い
内なる世界に引きこもるのか？
What do they think when they withdraw
into their inner world?
We will find out what they're really like!!
その素顔に迫る！
Otaku Summit: A Live
Debate Till Morning!
[Otaku Summit - A Live Debate Till Morning]
[Note: Spoof of Japanese TV discussion
program "Asa Made Nama TV."]
(司会)今日も朝までまいります！
As usual, we'll be going on until morning.
(神楽)ﾔﾊﾞｲ！
始まってしまったｱﾙ！
Oh no! It's started...
あれ？ おかしいｱﾙ…｡
(銀時)何やってんの？ お前｡
Huh? This is odd...
What are you doing?
I've got to tape Shinpachi's gallantry.
新八の勇姿を録画してやらないと｡
新八？
あ そういや今日来てねえよな｡
Shinpachi?
Come to think of it,
he hasn't come over today.
(新八)そもそも
ｵﾀｸがすべて引きこもりや➡
First off...
I'd like to correct the notion that all otaku
are hikikomori and NEETs in the making.
ﾆｰﾄの予備軍だという
その考え方は改めてほしいですね｡
[53 Idol Otaku - Captain Shimura]
ﾎﾞｸらのなかにだって
ちゃんと働いて➡
There are otaku amongst us who
work and function in society.
社会と向き合って生きてる
ｵﾀｸもいるんです！
What is he doing?
なにやってんの？ ｱｲﾂ…｡
Ah, I see...
ははぁ～ なるほど｡ え～ では
31番さんの意見はどうでしょう？
Umm...
Number 31, what's your opinion?
Well...
そうですね…｡
ｵﾀｸをやり玉にあげて➡
This show attempts to criticize and blame otaku
for causing Japan's current problems...
ことをﾎﾞｸらのせいにしようとする
この番組の基本ｽﾀﾝｽこそが➡
今の日本の問題を…｡
ははぁ わかりました…｡
All right, all right.
ｵｲｵｲ！ ﾒｯﾁｬ
うっとおしいﾔﾂになってるよ！
What's this? He's become
a really annoying guy!
I just want to get other people's
opinions, too...
これ間違いなく
視聴者に嫌われてるよ！
I'm sure the viewers definitely hate him!
だいたいね ｵﾀｸってひとくちで
すべて一緒にするのはおかしい！
First off, it's weird to group
all otaku into one category!
Oh no, it's getting heated! Come
on, where is that piece of junk?!
ﾔﾊﾞｲ 白熱してきたｱﾙ！
Now, now... A-Anyway, sit down, okay?
おい 動けﾎﾟﾝｺﾂ！
ﾎﾞｸらは ｱｲﾄﾞﾙっていう
一応 現実にいる存在を➡
We're supporting a pop idol,
something that's real.
応援しているけれど
意味がわからないのが➡
But what I don't understand is...
ｱﾆﾒとか ｹﾞｰﾑとか二次元の女の子に
恋をしている人たちですよね！
People who are in love with two-dimensional
girls from anime and games.
おい それどういう意味だ53番！
Hey! What do you mean
by that, Number 53?!
結局 二次元の女の子に恋
こがれてても成就しないでしょ！
A two-dimensional girl can never be attained
even if you're in love with her.
時間のﾑﾀﾞでしょ！
ふざけんな！
It's a waste of time.
No way! Shiori-chan is alive in my heart!
詩織ちゃんは
ｵﾚの心のなかに生きてるんだよ！
(土方)あっ ちょっと
異議があるんだけども いいかな？
Oh, I have an objection. May I speak?
Go right ahead.
(司会)どうぞ！
あの つまり53番は➡
[7 Anime Otaku - Toshi]
Umm... In short, Number
53 is trying to say
三次元ｵﾀｸは ﾎﾞｸら二次元ｵﾀｸより➡
that three-dimensional otaku are more realistic
than us two-dimensional otaku.
現実見てるって
いいたいんだろうけども➡
じゃあ 聞きたいんだけども➡
But let me ask you this...
ｷﾐは ｱｲﾄﾞﾙを応援していれば➡
Do you think supporting a pop idol
will help you get one to marry you?
いつか 結婚できるとでも
思っているのかな？
それは…｡
できないよね？
Well...
You can't, can you?
つまり
ｷﾐら三次元ｵﾀｸと 二次元ｵﾀｸは➡
In other words, us two-dimensional otaku
and you three-dimensional otaku
are both in love with something unattainable.
かなわない恋をしているっていう
ことにおいてさぁ➡
同じ穴のﾑｼﾞﾅであって…｡
いやいや…！
We're in the same boat.
No, no, you're wrong!
それは違うよ！
確かにぶっちゃけ➡
Indeed, it's impossible to marry a pop idol.
But it's not 100 percent guaranteed.
ｱｲﾄﾞﾙと結婚なんて無理だよ！
でも 100％じゃないじゃん！
ｷﾐらは 100％無理だけど！
いや ないよね 確実に｡
It's 100 percent impossible for you.
No, it's definitely impossible for you.
No, it's not! That's because
pop stars exist in real life.
いや なくはないよ！
現実に存在してるわけだから…｡
(土方)いや そういう
分不相応な考えそのものが➡
No, thinking about things beyond
your grasp like that
現実を見ていない…｡
(神楽)７番腹立つｱﾙな 新八いけ！
is absolute proof that you're
not being realistic.
Number 7 sure is annoying.
Go, Shinpachi!!
How dare you talk to
our captain like that?!
ﾃﾒｴ！ 隊長に
なにﾅﾒた口きいてんだ！
なんだと ｺﾗ！
What did you say?!
Whoa! The two-dimensional fans and the three-dimensional
fans have begun fighting each other.
(司会)ここで 二次元派と
三次元派のあいだで乱闘が…｡
できたｱﾙ！
It's done.
It's nicely melted!!
とろとろｱﾙ！
つ～か ﾊﾟﾝ焼いてたの？
You were toasting bread?
Weren't you supposed to be taping this?
録画じゃなかったの？ ん？
Huh? That guy...
あれ？ ｺｲﾂ どっかで見た顔だな｡
I've seen him somewhere...
["Otaku Are Talkative"]
[Shinsengumi Headquarters]
(隊士)
おい 聞いたか 土方さんの話｡
Hey, did you hear what happened
to Hijikata-san?
無期限の謹慎処分だって｡
He was placed under suspension
indefinitely.
局中法度を
犯したってんで 伊東さんは➡
He broke one of the Kyukuchu Hatto.
Ito-san insisted that he commit seppuku.
切腹を主張したらしいが➡
But the Chief and everyone else
persuaded him otherwise.
局長や みんなの説得で
それは免れたらしい｡
He's really being forced out, isn't he?
He probably won't be coming back.
事実上の更迭だよな｡
もうたぶん
戻ってこれねえんじゃないかな｡
伊東のﾔﾂが許すまいよ｡
Ito won't forgive him. Those two were
always at each other's throats.
あの２人 ずっと
いがみ合っていたからなぁ｡
いよいよｱｲﾂの時代か｡
It's finally his time to shine, huh?
ｳﾜｻじゃ 沖田さんも
伊東派についたらしいぜ｡
According to rumors, Okita-san
has sided with Ito's faction.
もう誰も 伊東には逆らえないよ｡
No one can oppose Ito anymore.
(伊東)意外だったよ 沖田君｡
How unexpected.
Okita-kun, I never expected you
to come over to my side.
ｷﾐが ﾎﾞｸの側についてくれるとは｡
ｷﾐらは真選組結成前からの
つきあいだと聞いていた｡
I heard that you two knew each other
before the Shinsengumi was formed.
ｷﾐは完全に
土方派だと思っていたが➡
I completely thought that you
were part of Hijikata's faction.
(沖田)土方派？
Hijikata's faction?
そんな派閥があったの
今の今まで知りやせんでしたよ｡
I wasn't aware that such
a faction ever existed.
(伊東)ﾌﾌｯ… 賢い男だ｡
You're a smart man.
望みは何かね？
What do you want?
もちろん 副長の座でさぁ｡
Naturally...
the Vice-Chief position.
ﾌｯ… ﾎﾞｸにつくかぎり
その望み 果たすこと 約束しよう｡
As long as you stick with
me, I promise to
grant you that wish.
Is that all right?
(篠原)よろしいので？
かまわんよ｡
It doesn't matter.
副長の座くらい くれてやる｡
I'll give him the position of Vice-Chief.
But if you do that, it'll defeat the
purpose of getting rid of Hijikata.
しかし それでは
土方を排した意味が…｡
篠原君 ｷﾐは ﾎﾞｸが 副長などという
役職を得たいがためだけに➡
Shinohara-kun...
Do you think I've started this silly
power struggle with that man
just so I could become Vice-Chief?
あの男と くだらん権力争いを➡
繰り広げていたとでも
思っているのか？
[Odd Jobs Gin]
あの… すみませんでした｡
Umm... I'm sorry.
まさか あんな所に あなたが
いるとは 思わなかったもので…｡
I never expected you to be there...
H-Hijikata-san.
ひ… 土方さん…｡
いや いいんだよ｡
No, it's all right.
I'm just glad my limited-edition figurine...
この限定ﾓﾃﾞﾙのﾌｨｷﾞｭｱ ﾄﾓｴ5000が
無事だっただけでもよしとするさ｡
Tomoe 5000 is safe.
Th-Thank you very much.
あ… ありがとうございます｡
ﾌﾌ…｡
えっ？ っていうか… えっ!?
ｵﾀｸ 土方さんですよね ﾎﾝﾄに…｡
Umm... What? Are you
really Hijikata-san?
What are you saying, Mr. Sakata?
[Note: Otaku often call each other by their
last names and the suffix "shi"  (Mr./Ms.)]
何を言ってるんだよ？ 坂田氏｡
坂田氏!?
"Mr. Sakata"?
As you can see...
このとおり！
正真正銘 土方 十四郎でござる｡
I am the real Toshiro Hijikata de gozaru.
[Note: Ending sentences with "de gozaru," (archaic form of "desu") was common amongst samurai and is popular speech among otaku.]
[Shogunate Special Armed Police, Shinsengumi
Vice-Chief Toshiro Hijikata]
ござる!?
あっ 神楽氏！ その中華服は…｡
"Gozaru"?
Oh, Miss Kagura...
That Chinese outfit!
さては 『魔法少女
ちゅうかなぱぱいや』の➡
Are you dressed up as Magical
Girl Chinese Papaya?
[Note: Refers to "Maho Shojo Chukana Paipai."
A live action girly series from the late 80's.]
ｺｽﾌﾟﾚでござるな！
かなり 完成度が高いね｡
That's incredibly accurate.
Could I take your picture?
ちょっと 写真
撮らせてもらっていいかな？
ﾌﾌｯ…｡ いいね いいよ｡
もう１枚 いい？
Nice. That's good. One more.
Why are you bashful?
なんで 照れてるの!?
おい！ どういうことだ？ これは｡
Hey, what's the meaning of this?
本物みたいですけど…
別人みたい｡
He's the real Hijikata-san...but
he's like a totally different person.
つうか あの 土方さん…｡
Anyway... Hijikata-san...
なんだい？ 志村氏｡
あの… 仕事はどうしたんですか？
What is it, Mr. Shimura?
Umm... What happened to work?
You're hanging around here
in the middle of the day.
昼間から こんな所 ﾌﾞﾗついて…｡
仕事？ あぁ… 真選組なら
ｸﾋﾞになったでござる｡
Work?
Oh, the Shinsengumi fired me.
What? You quit the Shinsengumi?!
Why?!
えぇ～っ!? 真選組をやめたの？
なんで!?
う～ん… まぁ
つまらない人間関係とか➡
Well, I started to hate trifling
human relations.
ｲﾔになっちゃってね｡
危険な仕事だし｡
The job was dangerous, too.
だいたい ﾎﾞｸに
向いてなかったんだよね｡
Besides, I'm not suited for it.
もともと ﾎﾞｸ
第１志望 ｱﾆﾒ声優だったしね｡
I originally wanted to become
an anime voice actor.
Really?! Is that true?!
そうなの!? そうだったの!?
Well, I guess, right now, I'm looking
for a way to get by without working.
まぁ 今は 働かないで
生きていける手段を➡
探してるって感じかな｡
働いたら負けだと思ってる｡
I think working is for losers.
ﾆｰﾄだ！ ﾆｰﾄの考え方だ!!
He's a NEET!! He's thinking
like a NEET!!
Oh yeah! Come to think of
it, you're like NEETs, too!
(土方)そうだ… 考えたら
ｷﾐらも ﾆｰﾄみたいなもんだろ？
誰が ﾆｰﾄだ！
一緒にするんじゃねえよ｡
Who are you calling a NEET?
Don't group us with them.
How about it? Do you want
to form a group with me?
(土方)どうかな？
ﾎﾞｸと一緒に ｻｰｸﾙやらないか？
今 ﾎﾞｸ 『TO LOVEる』の同人本
描いてるんだけど➡
Right now, I'm writing a
To Love-Ru dojinshi.
Mr. Sakata, you know a
lot about JUMP, right?
坂田氏は ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣に詳しいだろ？
一緒に 夏ｺﾐで
荒稼ぎしてみないか？
Want to make some money
at the Summer Comiket?
[Note: Summer Comiket is a Convention
for dojinshi (amateur comics).]
売れるか！
ｶﾞｷの落書きじゃねえか!!
This won't sell!! This looks
like a kid drew it!!
(土方)まいったな… 貯金
ほとんど ﾌｨｷﾞｭｱで使っちゃってね｡
I'm stumped. I used up most
of my savings on a figurine.
もう 刀でも売るしかないか｡
I guess I have to sell my sword.
最低なんですけど この人！
He's really pathetic! He's trying to sell
his samurai soul to get a figurine!!
ﾌｨｷﾞｭｱのために 侍の魂
売ろうとしてるんですけど！
I've tried to sell it many times,
but I can't seem to let go of it.
もう 何度も
売ろうとしてるんだけど➡
なんか どうしても
手放せないんだよ｡
店の人が 妖刀とか言ってたけど
まさかね…｡
The guy at the store said that it was a cursed
demonic sword, but that can't be...
Oh! Do you think that maybe I'll
wake up in the morning to find
(土方)あっ！ ひょっとして
ある朝 目覚めたら➡
this demonic sword has changed into
a beautiful girl sleeping next to me?
妖刀が美少女に変わって
ﾎﾞｸの隣で寝てて…｡
Oh! I'm beginning to love that idea...
やべっ！ 萌えてきたんですけど｡
[Swordsmith]
This blade pattern on the
front and the back...
(鉄子)この表と裏 揃った刃紋…｡
(鉄子)間違いない｡ 村麻紗だ｡
村麻紗？
There's no mistake. This is Muramasha.
[Note: Spoof of legendary evil sword "Muramasa."]
Muramasha?
It is a famous sword forged by Muramasha Senko,
a swordsmith from the Muromachi Era.
[Note: Spoof of legendary swordsmith
"Senko Muramasa."]
(鉄子)室町時代の刀匠
千子 村麻紗によって➡
打たれた名刀だ｡
It is said to cut incredibly well.
その切れ味もさることながら➡
It is also known as a demonic sword
that devours human souls.
人の魂を食らう
妖刀としても知られている｡
A demonic sword? Is it really
a demonic sword?!
妖刀!? 本当に妖刀でござるか？
中から 美少女が
出てきたりするでござるか!?
Will a beautiful girl come out of it?!
Well... Umm...
いや あの…｡
A demonic sword?
妖刀って… いったい
どんな妖刀だっていうんですか？
What kind of demonic sword is it?
母親に 村麻紗で斬られた➡
It apparently harbors the grudge
of a hikikomori boy
who was slain by his mother
with the Muramasha.
引きこもりの息子の怨念が
宿っているらしい｡
つうか どんな妖刀!?
What kind of demonic sword is that?!
伝説では ふだんは不登校で
ｱﾆﾒばっか観てるくせに➡
According to legend, the son
never went to school...
And always watched anime. But he said
he wanted to go on a school trip.
修学旅行だけ行きたい と
言い出したらしい｡
As expected, his mother snapped.
さすがに 母親もｷﾚて…｡ そのとき
使われたのが 村麻紗なんだ｡
Muramasha is the sword she used.
What a realistic legend! That
happened recently, didn't it?!
どんだけ 具体的な伝説!?
最近だよね それ！
ﾆｭｰｽでやってそうだよね それ！
That sounds like it was on
the news, doesn't it?!
Those who carry Muramasha
at their sides
(鉄子)村麻紗を
一度 腰に帯びた者は➡
will become possessed by the
grudge of the hikikomori son.
引きこもりの息子の怨念に
取り憑かれ➡
Their interest in anime and two-dimensional
media will increase,
ｱﾆﾒ および 二次元ﾒﾃﾞｨｱに対する
興味が増幅され➡
and their interest in work and fighting
will decrease proportionately.
それと反比例し 働く意欲
戦う意志は 薄弱になっていく｡
In other words, he'll become
a hopeless otaku.
(鉄子)すなわち ﾍﾀﾚたｵﾀｸになる｡
But there are many counterfeits
of this sword.
だが 贋作も多い刀だ｡
Even if it is a real sword,
たとえ 本物だとしても ｺｲﾂが➡
there's an even lower chance that
it's the sword of legend. But...
その伝説の代物だという可能性は
さらに低いだろう｡
だが ｺｲﾂが 正真正銘
本物の 妖刀 村麻紗なら➡
If this is the real demon sword...
もはや その男に 本来の魂は
残っていないかもしれない｡
There may not be anything left
of that man's original soul.
(鉄子)妖刀に食い尽くされ➡
It's likely the demonic sword has devoured him
and he's already become a different person.
既に 別人となっていても
何ら おかしくない｡
もう 本来のｿｲﾂは
戻ってくることはないかもしれ…｡
He'll probably never return
to his former self.
(伊東)ｷﾐもﾎﾞｸを
理解しえないか 篠原君｡
Do you understand me, Shinohara-kun?
武士にとって
最大の不幸は何だと思う？
What do you think is the greatest
misfortune for a warrior?
(伊東)それは
理解されないことさ｡
It's the misfortune of not
being understood.
いくら才能を
持ち合わせていようと➡
No matter how much skill you have...
いくら努力していようと➡
No matter how hard you try, you
will never be judged properly.
それに見合うだけの
評価をされない｡
(伊東)器に見合うだけの
ｴｻが もらえない｡
You will never be given food
that is suited for your stature.
これほどの不幸は ない｡
There is no greater misfortune.
(伊東)趙の李牧しかり
南宋の岳飛しかり｡
Like Li Mu of Zhao and Yue
Fei of Southern Song...
愚鈍な君主に仕え その才とともに
消えていった名将の➡
There were many great generals who
faded away along with their skills...
While serving stupid rulers.
なんと多いことか… ﾎﾞｸも また
真の理解者を得なかった｡
I also never had someone
who truly understood me.
学問所で神童と
うたわれていたときも➡
Even when I was called a
child prodigy at school,
名門 北斗流で皆伝を得
塾頭に任じられたときも…｡
or when I mastered the distinguished Hokuto Itto,
ついには 時流に乗り
攘夷の徒とさえ交わった｡
I went along with the times and even associated
with Anti-Foreigner Faction members.
だが どこへ行こうとも ﾎﾞｸの器が
満たされることはなかった｡
But wherever I went, nothing
was satisfying enough.
それが まさか
こんなところで出会えるとはな｡
I never thought that I
would find it here.
あの男こそ ﾎﾞｸの最大の理解者だ｡
That man understands me the most.
あの男は知っている｡ ﾎﾞｸが
真選組に収まる器ではないことを｡
That man knows I'm too good
for the Shinsengumi.
ﾎﾞｸが 近藤ごときの下で
終わる男ではないことを｡
He knows that I will not end
up serving the likes of Kondo.
ﾎﾞｸの渇きを…｡
He knows what I thirst for...
ｼｬ～ｯ!
(猫の鳴き声)
ﾎﾞｸにとって最大の不幸は➡
My greatest misfortune is that the person who
understands me the most is my enemy.
最大の理解者が
敵だった ということさ｡
まぁ いい｡ 理解できる者が
いないなら 自ら認めさせるまで｡
Well, that's fine.
If there isn't anyone who understands me,
I just have to make everyone recognize me.
最も危険な男は消えた｡ あとは➡
The most dangerous man is gone.
All that's left
近藤 勲を暗殺し
真選組を我がものにする！
is to kill Isao Kondo and make
the Shinsengumi mine.
《山崎:あの男… やはり
副長の言うとおり…｡
That man... It's as the Vice-Chief said...
知らせねば 副長に…
早く副長に知らせねば…》
I need to tell the Vice-Chief... I need to
let the Vice-Chief know immediately.
ﾌ～ｯ…｡
お前… ひょっとして…！
You... Could it be?!
やれやれ 最後の１本
吸いにきたら➡
My, my, I came to smoke
my last cigarette.
目の前にいるのが
よりによって ﾃﾒｴらたぁ…➡
Of all the people to last see...
I've become a total degenerate.
ｵﾚも ﾔｷが回ったもんだ｡
まぁ いい｡
Oh well... This is it for me... I'll cling
onto anything, even straw...
[Note: From the proverb, "A drowning
man will grasp at a straw."]
ｺｲﾂで 最後だ｡ ﾜﾗだろうが
何だろうが すがってやらぁ…｡
(土方)いいか？ ﾃﾒｴらに
最初で最後の頼みがある｡
Listen up. This is my first
and last request for you.
(山崎)まさか 伊東のﾔﾂ…
ﾔﾂらと手を結んでいたなんて｡
I never expected...
Ito to be allied with them.
副長に… 早く！ 副長に…！
I need to tell the Vice-Chief
immediately...
The Vice-Chief ...
(土方)頼む…｡
Please...
The Shinsengumi...
真選組を… ｵﾚの…
ｵﾚたちの真選組を…➡
My... Our Shinsengumi...
護って…➡
Protect it...
くれ…｡
Please...
ぐほっ… お… お前は…➡
Y-You're...
鬼兵隊… 人斬り… 河上 万斉…｡
The Kiheitai... Swordsman...
Bansai...Kawakami...
♪♪～
(山崎)い… 伊東…｡
I-Ito...
ｷ… ｷｻﾏ… 敵と内通していたか…｡
You bastard...
You were secretly associating
with the enemy.
山崎君｡ ｷﾐたちのように
斬り合いばかりじゃ➡
Yamazaki-kun, the world won't change
if we keep on sword fighting like you.
世の中は変わらん｡
もっと利口にならねば｡
We must be smarter.
いくら剣をふるったところで
犯罪は撲滅できやしない｡
No matter how much we swing our swords,
we cannot stamp out crime.
(伊東)もっと言えば
彼らが いなければ ﾎﾞｸら警察も➡
Furthermore, you mustn't forget
that if they weren't around,
there would be no use for us police.
必要なくなってしまうことを
忘れてはいけない｡
ﾎﾞｸらは もっと互いに うまく
つきあっていけるはずなんだ｡
I'm sure it would be better for
us to work with each other.
双方の利潤を満たし
均衡を保つﾊﾟｰﾄﾅｰとして｡
We can become partners who work for each
other's profit and maintain balance.
ｷﾐの上司のようなやり方では
真選組は これ以上 強くはならん｡
The Shinsengumi won't become
any stronger if we
continue to do things the
way your superior does.
ﾎﾞｸの手によって
真選組は生まれ変わるんだ｡
I will change the Shinsengumi.
もっと強くて もっと大きく…｡
It'll become stronger and bigger.
そうして この 伊東 鴨太郎が➡
And I, Kamotaro Ito, will become the
spear that shows our potential
器を天下に示すための
方舟となってもらう！
to take control of the country.
やりたきゃ やりなよ…｡
Do what you want...
(山崎)だが １つ言っとく｡
But let me say this.
ｱﾝﾀが どれほどの
器の持ち主かなんて➡
We may be uneducated and can't
tell how skilled you are...
学のないｵﾚたちには わからんよ｡
だが 士道も節操も
もちあわせない➡
But no one will follow an empty vessel
with no bushido or principles.
空っぽの器になんて
誰もついていかんよ…｡
ｵﾚは あの人たちに
ついていかせてもらうわ｡
I'll follow them...
最後… まで｡
Until the end...
ﾌﾌ… 死ぬ最後のときまで
ﾔﾂらに知らせようと前進する｡
You'll continue on struggling to inform them
of what you've discovered until the very end.
それが監察である ｷﾐの士道だと？
As their spy, are you saying
that is part of your bushido?
万斉殿… あとは頼む｡
Bansai-dono, I leave the rest to you.
ｷﾐには 攘夷浪士と戦い
討ち死にした➡
I'll give you the honor of dying in a battle
against an Anti-Foreigner Faction member.
名誉の殉死を与えよう｡
よかったな… ｷﾐらの大好きな
士道とやらが通せるんだ｡
Aren't you glad? You can maintain
that bushido you love so much.
(伊東)上司たちにも
しっかり伝えておいてやろう｡
I'll be sure to tell that to your superiors.
いや… 必要ないか｡
No...
I suppose there's no need for that.
彼らも すぐに ｷﾐのところへ
いくことになるのだから｡
They'll be headed to where
you're going soon enough.
(斬る音)
There's something going on within
the Shinsengumi right now.
真選組内で 今 何かが起きている｡
そういうことですか？
Is that it?
もしかして土方さんも そのせいで
真選組を ｸﾋﾞになったんじゃ…｡
Do you think Hijikata-san was fired from
the Shinsengumi because of that?
Who knows? Well, whatever happens,
it's none of our business.
さあな… まぁ
何が起きてようが➡
ｵﾚたちにゃ関係ねえだろ｡
これ以上 深入りはよそうや｡
Let's avoid getting involved any further.
でも あの土方さんが➡
But Hijikata-san asked us
of all people to help him.
よりによって ﾎﾞｸらに
頼みごとをするなんて…｡
あの ﾌﾟﾗｲﾄﾞの高い土方さんが
恥も外聞も捨てて➡
Hijikata is very prideful.
For him to put aside his
shame and self-respect,
人にものを頼むなんて
よっぽどのことが…｡
and ask someone to do something for
him... It must be pretty serious...
Umm...
(土方)あの…
坂田氏 悪いんだが➡
Excuse me, Mr. Sakata, but...
実は 明日
ﾚｱﾓﾉの限定美少女ﾌｨｷﾞｭｱの➡
A rare limited-edition figurine
is going on sale tomorrow.
即売会があるんだけど➡
１人１個までしか
売ってくれないんだ｡
It's limited to one per customer.
しかし 拙者としては
保存用と鑑賞用➡
But I want to buy three: one to preserve,
one to look at, and one to use.
そして 実用用に
３個揃えておきたいところでね➡
そこで 諸君らに指令を下す｡
拙者と一緒に…｡
So I order you to come with me...
ﾃﾒｴは 少しは 恥や外聞を覚えろ！
You should get some shame
and self-respect!
(神楽)実用って
何に使うつもりだ!?
"To use"? What are you
planning to use it for?!
心配してんのが
ｱﾎらしくなってくんだろうが！
I feel stupid for worrying about you!!
[Shinsengumi]
副長！
(隊士)ようやく見つけた！
Vice-Chief ...
We finally found you.
大変なんです 副長！
Bad news, Vice-Chief!
Come back to the squad immediately.
すぐに隊に戻ってください！
何かあったんですか？
What happened?
山崎さんが… 山崎さんが
何者かに殺害されました！
Yamazaki-san... Yamazaki-san...
Someone killed him.
Y-Yamazaki-san?!
や… 山崎さんが!?
(隊士)屯所のはずれで➡
We found him on the ground, covered
in blood just outside the headquarters.
血まみれで倒れているところを
発見されたんですが…➡
もう そのときには…｡
By that time...
下手人は まだ
見つかっておりません！
We still haven't found the killer.
Anyway...
とにかく 一度 屯所に
戻ってきてください！
Come back with us to the headquarters.
ええっ！ でも
拙者 ｸﾋﾞになった身だし…｡
Huh?
But I was fired...
そんなこと言ってる
場合じゃないでしょ！
Now's not the time to be saying that.
(隊士)さあ 早く！
副長も 山崎のところへ…！
Come on, quickly...
Vice-Chief...
Come join Yamazaki...
♪♪～
しまった！ 逃げられた！
追え～！
Damn! They got away!
After them!!
(土方)ｲﾀﾀﾀ… 坂田氏！
Ow,ow,ow,ow,ow,ow. Mr. Sakata,
(土方)Ｇｼﾞｬﾝの肩の部分が
くいこんでるぅ！
the shoulder portion of my denim
jacket is grinding into me!!
さながら 『ﾍﾞﾙｾﾙｸ』のｶﾞｯﾂがごとく
腕がちぎれそうだ！
My arms feel like they're going to
rip off just like Guts from Berserk!!
[Note: Guts is the main character of Berserk,
a popular manga from Hakusensha.]
うるせえ！ ﾃﾒｴ 黙ってろぃ！
Shut up!! You be quiet!!
What was the meaning of that?!
どういうことだ あれ!?
なんで 真選組が土方さんを!?
Why is the Shinsengumi after Hijikata?!
坂田氏…！
Mr. Sakata!
♪♪～
あわばば 神楽氏！ すごいよ！
Whoa, Miss Kagura. That was amazing!
さながら ｢ﾄﾞｸﾀｰｽﾗﾝﾌﾟ｣
ｱﾗﾚ氏の再来のごとく…｡
This is like the return of Miss
Arale from Dr. Slump...
[Note: Dr. Slump is a manga by Akira
Toriyama, author of Dragon Ball.]
うるせえ！ 誰か ｿｲﾂを黙らせろ！
Shut up!! Someone shut this guy up!!
♪♪～
あ～ あ～ こちら三番隊
こちら三番隊｡
This is Third Squad. This is Third
Squad. Come in. Over.
応答願います どうぞ！
[TEL](隊士)土方は見つかったか？
Did you find Hijikata?
見つかりましたが
超かわいくて強い味方が➡
We found him, but we were no match
for his incredibly cute and strong ally.
ついてまして
敵いませんでした！
どうぞｱﾙ！
[TEL]ｱﾙ？
Over, uh-huh.
"Uh-huh"?
[TEL]どんな手を使ってでも 殺せ｡
Do whatever it takes to kill him.
近藤を消したとしても
土方がいたのでは 意味がない｡
Even if we kill Kondo, it'll be
meaningless if Hijikata's still around.
[TEL]近藤暗殺を前に
不安要素は すべて除く｡
Get rid of all the dangerous elements
before we assassinate Kondo.
[TEL]近藤 土方 両者が消えれば➡
Once Kondo and Hijikata are both gone,
the entire Shinsengumi will become
faithful to the Ito faction.
真選組は残らず すべて
伊東派に恭順するはず｡
近藤さん 土方さんを暗殺!?
They're planning to assassinate
Kondo-san and Hijikata-san?!
Don't let any other squad members
aside from us find out.
[TEL]我ら以外の隊士に
気づかれるなよ｡
[TEL]あくまで 攘夷浪士の犯行に
見せかけるのだ｡
Make it look as if Anti-Foreigner
Faction members did it.
[TEL]この段階で
伊東さんの計画が 露見すれば➡
If Ito-san's plan is exposed at this stage,
the Shinsengumi will be split in two.
真選組が 真っ二つに割れる｡
[TEL]近藤のほうは
半ば 成功したようなものだ｡
Kondo's assassination
looks to be a success.
[TEL]伊東さんの仕込んだとおり➡
Right now, he's on a train
heading to an expedition
隊士募集の遠征につき
すでに列車の中｡
to recruit squad members,
just as Ito-san planned.
[TEL]つき従う隊士は
すべて我々の仲間｡
All of the squad members
with him are allied with us.
He's by himself...
[TEL]ﾔﾂは たった１人だ｡
Kondo is
[TEL]近藤の 地獄行きは 決まった｡
going to hell.
(近藤)久しぶりだな
武州に帰るのは｡
It's been a while since I've
gone back to Bushu.
[Note: Also known as Musashi Province. Today, it
comprises of Tokyo, Saitama and part of Kanagawa.]
あそこは ｵﾚや ﾄｼや
総悟の生まれ育ったところでね➡
That's where Toshi, Sogo and I grew up.
どいつも ｺｲﾂも
ｹﾝｶばかりしてる➡
It was a rough place where
there were always fights.
荒れたところだった｡
Come to think of it, it's no different
from what we're doing now.
考えてみたら やってることは
今と変わらんな｡
たまに 不安になる｡
Sometimes I get anxious.
ｵﾚは あの頃から ちょっとは
ﾏｼなﾔﾂになれたのかって｡
I could have been a better
guy back then.
I could have advanced a little.
少しは 前に 進めているのかって｡
ｷﾐは 立派な侍だ｡
You're a wonderful samurai.
I've never met a person
more honest than you.
ﾎﾞｸは ｷﾐほど
清廉な人物に 会ったことがない｡
I suppose I could call you immaculate.
無垢… ともいうのかな｡
ｷﾐは 白い布のようなものだな｡
You're like a white cloth.
何ものも受け入れ
何色にも染まる｡
You accept anything and
are colored by all colors.
The Shinsengumi
真選組とは きっと
その白い布に➡
is a flag made of a white cloth onto which
everyone may project his colors.
皆が それぞれの色で
思いを描いた 御旗なのだろう｡
比べて ﾎﾞｸの色は 黒だ｡
In comparison, my color is black.
何ものにも 染まらないし➡
I'm not colored by anything,
and I turn everything black.
すべてを 黒く
塗りつぶしてしまう｡
どこへ行っても 黒しか残らない｡
Only black remains, no matter where I go.
私の通った跡は
すべて私の色になってしまう｡
Everywhere I go becomes my color.
(伊東)近藤さん… すまないね｡
Kondo-san, I'm sorry.
ｷﾐたちの御旗は➡
Your flag has become pitch black.
もう真っ黒に
なってしまったんだよ｡
ｸｸｸ… わ～はっはっは!!
さすが先生
おもしろいことを言うなぁ！
As expected, Sensei.
You say interesting things.
ｵﾚたちが 真っ黒に染まった？
We've become pitch black?
I see. That would be true
if I were a white cloth.
なるほど
ｵﾚが 白い布だとするならば➡
確かに そうかもな｡
だが ｵﾚなんざ➡
But I'm...
a loincloth that's full of frizzy hair. A white flag?
いいところ 縮れ毛だらけの
ふんどしってとこかなぁ｡
白い御旗？
ﾊｯ そんな
甘っちょろいもんじゃないさ｡
I'm not that naïve.
先生のまわりにいる連中は
知らんが ﾔﾂらは 違う｡
I don't know about those around
you, but they're different.
ﾔﾂらは 色なんて呼べる
代物じゃねえ｡
They can't be called a color.
If anything, they're grime.
言ってみりゃあ 垢だよ｡
They're stains that you can't remove,
no matter how much you wash.
洗ってもとれねえ
染みついちまった汚れだ｡
They're persistent and can't
be removed by washing.
しつこくて 洗っても
とれねえもんだから➡
しまいに 愛着まで
わいてきやがって➡
I ended up becoming attached
to them. It's a real bother.
困ったもんだよ｡
だが 汚れも 寄せ集まって➡
But the stains began to gather, and as
time passed, they became visible.
年季が入るうちに
見られるようになってきてね｡
いつの間にやら
立派な御旗になっていやがった｡
Before I knew it, they'd become
a splendid flag.
学もねえし 思想もねえ｡
They're uneducated and have no ideals.
They act according to emotion
more than logic.
理屈より
感情で動くような連中だ｡
ﾊｯ 何を考えてるか わからん
得体の知れない連中だ｡
I don't often know what they're thinking.
They're mysterious guys.
先生 ｱﾝﾀの手には 負えない｡
Sensei, you...
can't control them.
ﾔﾂらは 何色にも
塗り潰せないし➡
They can't be colored or
affected by anything.
何ものにも 染まらん｡
Okita-kun, what are you doing?
(伊東)沖田君 何をやっている？
ｷﾐは 見張りのはず…｡
You're supposed to be keeping watch.
ﾃﾒｴは 何やってんだ？
What are you doing?
ﾃﾒｴが何やってんだって
聞いてんだ ｸｿ野郎｡
I'm asking you what you're
doing, you piece of shit.
沖田君！
伊東先生に なんて口を！
Okita-kun...
How dare you talk like that to Ito Sensei?!
手を離せ｡
うわ!?
Let go.
その人から 手を離せって
言ってんだ！
I said, let go of him!!
[To be continued]
[Preview]
Hijikata-san!! Get a hold
of yourself, Hijikata-san!!
It's none of my concern...
It's of no concern...
At this rate, you may lose all the
people and things you hold dear!!
["There's a Thin Line Between
Strengths and Weaknesses"]
[Ito has been in contact with the Kiheitai. His plan
is to assassinate Kondo, the Shinsengumi's Chief.]
[Hijikata has become Toshi. Gintoki and the others
drag him along as they chase after the train!!]]